## **Austen Tucker CSM**

<u>Austen@thearcades.me</u>
6121 N Sheridan Rd. #2h, Chicago, IL 60660
1-317-410-7271

#### **EXPERIENCE SUMMARY**

Multitalented scrum master, business analyst, javascript developer, and project manager with fifteen years of experience developing software across multiple industry verticals. They are most at home in environments that allow them to utilize a unique, out-of-the-box skillset as techie, teacher, servant leader, and creative person to devise elegant solutions to inelegant problems.

#### **AREAS OF EXPERTISE**

- Complete agile and waterfall software development lifecycle experience in tightly regulated business and government environments
- · Agile coach and mentor for multiple teams with both remote and on-site members
- Planning messaging, approach, and market strategy for proposals, software demonstrations, and team presentations with C-suite executives, SMEs and other stakeholders
- Generating documentation including user stories, use cases, gap analyses, business needs assessments, test plans, training materials, and helpdesk documentation
- Production work with javascript, bootstrap, angular, jquery, and postgres
- Proficient hobbyist in Node.js, Express, MongoDB Python, Flask, Postman, Amazon Lambdas
- · Tracking software: Google Analytics, Hotjar, Datadog, Grafana, Tableau
- Work Tracking software: Jira, Confluence, Trello, Mural
- Volunteer testing and documentation contributor to Simply Plural's public API. Simply Plural is an application used by people with Dissociative Identity Disorder (DID) to manage their alters.
- Created a number of small web tools with people with DID in mind: plug-and-play system introduction websites, low-friction ways to check which alter is fronting in friends' systems, and automation of sending useful system information to therapists

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

## Arity, Chicago, Illinois

Senior Scrummaster and Agile Coach, June 2020 to Present

Acting in both a scrummaster and coaching role across the Agile Delivery department. Arity was undergoing a large refactoring project of how their teams were structured and held accountable, and I was brought on to bring fresh ideas from my time in startups into an org that has a heavy tie to a fortune 100 company.

- Simplified the quarterly planning process for one of these segments to focus leaders and decisionmakers on creating end-user value and proving that value with data. The new process reduced the
  number of active projects, but increased our confidence in delivery and allowed quarterly planning to be
  completed within two weeks.
- Coached teams to stay focused on outcomes instead of task lists. As an example of results from this, one team turned a "frivolous" experiment into a exponential reduction in processing power required to analyze and make predictions on trip data.
- Coached individual scrum masters on ways to push past the process and get teams to collaborate on the real problems at hand. Previous mentees from this job went on to senior / lead scrummaster duties at well known startups.
- Created and presented easy-to-digest presentations about the advantages of Agile that were presented at company-wide learn day presentations.

## Kazoo, Chicago, Illinois

Senior Scrummaster and Head of Agile PMO, January 2019 to June 2020

Senior scrummaster responsible for coaching an organization recently trained on scrum into a high-functioning agile org. Company had just embarked on a two-year plan to reconcile two orgs as a single new brand.

- Established "Weather Station" PMO model to inform management of project status. This model emphasized the importance of prioritization and agile methodology; the resulting visibility reduced the number of in-flight projects by 50% and increased feature delivery throughput by a similar factor.
- Implemented minor changes to team workflow that increased visibility and accountability for team members. As a result, velocity increased by 100% and teams delivered more features in a quarter than they had in the previous year.
- Coached two direct reports on how to be better scrummasters.

# **Guaranteed Rate, Chicago, Illinois**

Scrummaster and Project Lead, November 2015 to December 2018

Scrummaster for multiple, autonomous backend development teams working in postgres, redis, angular, clojure, and bootstrap. Team deliverable included a data mining tool that generated \$1.5B in locked loans and Gateless, a portal targeting realtors.

- Took on a cross-team, two-year initiative for app package generation that had stalled prior to delivery. Worked with engineers to rescope the project, define clear milestones, and communicate to executives the blockers and risks that threatened project delivery. Once rebased the project delivered an MVP within two months and reduced time to create app packages by 75%.
- Worked with business stakeholders to develop a measurement plan for Gateless, a web app
  designed to help realtors and referral partners, using Google Analytics and Hotjar. Metrics
  helped the team make a case for removing features that were used by < 1% of visitors.</li>

## **OTHER EXPERIENCE**

Chicago Housing Authority, Chicago, Illinois, Business Analyst and Scrum Master, October 2012 to October 2015

Technology Partnership Group, Indianapolis, Indiana Business Analyst, May 2009 to September 2012 Bell Techlogix, Indianapolis, Indiana: Call Center Analyst, February 2009 to May 2009 AOTMP, Indianapolis, Indiana: Telecom Research Writer, September 2008 to February 2009 Cardinal Ritter High School, Indianapolis, Indiana: 10th Grade English Teacher, August 2007 to June 2008

## **EDUCATION/CERTIFICATION**

Wabash College, Cum Laude, English and Teacher Education

#### **PERSONAL INTERESTS**

Published Novelist: Bait and Switch, The Painted Cat

Recurring guest on <u>WordCrash</u>, a podcast gameshow where writers compete to make the best story pitch

Create community learning materials for people who live with DID so that they can balance their disorder against their desire for healthy, productive work lives